in linkedin.com/in/makmendelson/

Overview

14+ years experience designing and 2+ years experience developing effective, appealing, & easy-to-use websites & software applications. Well-versed in cross-discipline communication & teamwork.

Skills English • Russian • Spanish

User Experience & User Interface Design • Visual & Graphic Design • Front-End Design & Development • Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop • HTML • CSS • Javascript • jQuery • Bootstrap C# • Razor • Telerik Blazor • Agile • Git • Microsoft Visual Studio 2022 • SQL Server • Wireframing Product Design & Development • Game Design & Development • Concept Art

Experience

CANDA Solutions, LLC.

http://candasolutions.com

Clients: Department of Homeland Security (DHS), Booz Allen Hamilton, Insight Global, CACI, RTI

Developer

September 2023 — October 2024

- Designed and developed, from inception to delivery, an all-in-one, comprehensive, web-based platform for internal use by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and other clients, with marked improvements over clients' previous tools in the areas of user experience and attractive & intuitive design.
 - o Used Telerik Blazor, Razor, C#, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Continued in my role of maintaining & updating business aid documents using Adobe Illustrator
- Current **DHS Public Trust clearance**

Contractor - Designer & Developer

February 2017 — September 2023

- Designed, implemented, and maintained HubSpot-integrated Wordpress sites (FreshHaystack, PerSec Express, CANDA Solutions), until I transitioned into my role as a full-time developer.
- Designed & Wireframed mock-ups, and implemented Front-End designs for an online Dashboard for Employee Management, Onboarding, and Continuous Investigations.
 - Used Balsamiq, Adobe Illustrator, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Produced & continuously updated numerous detailed visual and business aids, allowing CANDA to demonstrate to their clients, with clarity, the breadth of the products and services they offer.
 - Marketing & Booth materials, Digital & Printed explanatory aids & Posters, Branding for CANDA products: FreshHaystack & PerSec Express
 - Used Adobe Illustrator
- Consulted on Mobile application design

Buchanan & Edwards

http://buchanan-edwards.com/

User Interface Consultant and Tester

December 2014 — June 2016

- Consulted, produced high-fidelity mock-ups, and tested User Interfaces in the development of a Knowledge Management Tool web application for the Department of State (DOS)
- Collaborated with Business Analysts to collect, define, and document client requirements
- Collaborated with Developers to determine best implementation strategies, and to ensure product is always inline with current design mock-ups
- Developed Branding and designed Stationary with Adobe Illustrator
- Had **DOD SECRET clearance** (EXPIRED June 2018)

Gradient Studios, LLC.

http://www.gradientstudios.com April 2010 — February 2014

2002 - 2006

Co-Founder and Visual Artist

- Co-founded Gradient Studios, LLC.
- Developed Start-to-Finish, and Shipped two games of our own IP
- Determined and Designed aesthetics for several games
- Created UI and game assets for several games, with Adobe Illustrator and Blender
- Created promotional material: trailer/gameplay videos, posters, booth design w/ Illustrator & After Effects
- Assisted in securing seed funding from Accomplice (formerly of Altas Ventures)

Education

Gilman School

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute BS, Games & Simulation Arts & Sciences, Concentration in Electronic Arts